David Andrianarivo

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

andrianarivo.david@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Detail-oriented with a growth mindset and +3 years of industry experience. Eager to join XYZ to build creative solutions for their business. A Full-stack software developer using Rails and React that brings unique traits to the table: collaboration and leadership.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Railway, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Mob Programming

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full-stack Web Developer & Mentor

Remote March 2023 – Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building eight full-stack projects both independently and via pair programming.

<u>DocConnect</u> — Help users to book an appointment with a doctor easily and securely with a web app.

• Built with: Rails, Postgresql, React, Redux, Tailwind

<u>Space Traveler's Hub</u> — A web application for a company that provides commercial and scientific space travel services. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space missions.

Built with: React, Bootstrap

MICROVERSE
Mentor (Volunteer)

Remote April 2023 – Present

- Mentored +10 junior web developers, providing technical support through Slack and Github.
- Improvements to code organization, code quality and overall performance by 15%.
- Provided advice and tips to +10 students to maintain longevity in the program.

FUTURMAP DATA

Android Software Engineer

Antananarivo, Madagascar

October 2020 - December 2022

- Accomplished adhering to industry standards, as measured by the company's performance indicator, by doing workshops.
- Accomplished clients' mobile app dreams, as measured by the client's finance business unit, through online monitoring after deployment.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

March 2023 - December 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ISPM

Master 2, Computer Science

December 2016 - December 2022

- WAN monitoring using the SNMP protocol with Centreon.
- Has been at the top of the class consecutively for 5 years at the university.